<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Uncategorized &#8211; Reach Your Life</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../../index.html</link>
	<description>hiểu rõ chính mình, định hình tương lai, đạt được hạnh phúc</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 02:58:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/01/cropped-image_2024-01-17_173413523-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Uncategorized &#8211; Reach Your Life</title>
	<link>./../../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">228209872</site>	<item>
		<title>What is logical thinking? The role and methods of training logical thinking ability.</title>
		<link>./../../../what-is-logical-thinking-the-role-and-methods-of-training-logical-thinking-ability/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../what-is-logical-thinking-the-role-and-methods-of-training-logical-thinking-ability/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ReachYL]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 02:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../../index.html?p=1663</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the most special things that sets humans apart from other animals is that we not only act on instinct, but also rely on the ability to think and perceive. In real life, all of our activities are through the thinking of the brain. We always think, plan when starting to do something. From &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>One of the most special things that sets humans apart from other animals is that we not only act on instinct, but also rely on the ability to think and perceive. In real life, all of our activities are through the thinking of the brain. We always think, plan when starting to do something.</p>



<p>From that, it is evident that the result of thinking has a tremendous impact on our behavior and work methods, the effectiveness of what we do depends a great deal on thinking. So, what is logical thinking, its role, and methods of training logical thinking?</p>



<div class="wp-block-rank-math-toc-block" id="rank-math-toc"><h2>Table of Contents</h2><nav><ul><li class=""><a href="#1-what-is-logic-thinking">1. What is logic thinking.</a></li><li class=""><a href="#2-the-role-of-logical-thinking-in-life">2. The role of logical thinking in life.</a></li><li class=""><a href="#3-methods-for-training-logical-thinking-ability">3. Methods for training logical thinking ability.</a><ul><li class=""><a href="#always-start-with-the-questions-why-and-how">Always start with the questions &#8220;Why?&#8221; and &#8220;How?&#8221;.</a></li><li class=""><a href="#improve-your-own-knowledge">Improve your own knowledge.</a></li><li class=""><a href="#develop-logical-thinking-through-debate-and-exchange">Develop logical thinking through debate and exchange.</a></li><li class=""><a href="#train-logical-thinking-through-real-life-experiences-and-issues">Train logical thinking through real-life experiences and issues.</a></li></ul></li><li class=""><a href="#4-conclusion">4. Conclusion.</a></li></ul></nav></div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-what-is-logic-thinking"><strong>1. What is logic thinking.</strong></h2>



<p>Logical thinking is the process by which human beings analyze, reason, evaluate information, and string together information to create systematic connections based on their own knowledge, experience, evidence, and real-life events to solve problems at work and make decisions in life.</p>



<p>Logical thinking helps people to build for themselves a system of analysis, argumentation, and speculation, thereby making decisions that help achieve desired results.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-the-role-of-logical-thinking-in-life">2. The role of logical thinking in life.</h2>



<p>It can be affirmed that logical thinking plays a crucial role in all success. Every day, we use logical thinking to participate in activities.</p>



<p>It supports people to analyze information in a logical and systematic way. By looking at the issue from many different angles, we will gather the necessary data and information, from which we can clearly identify the problem.</p>



<p>From there, we can infer, link those elements together in a systematic way, based on criteria to find solutions to the problem.</p>



<p>In addition, you also have the ability to assess the risks, feasibility, and effectiveness of the solutions you consider. From there, you can choose a method to limit risks and still achieve your goals.</p>



<p>For example, when we go to the supermarket to buy things with a certain amount of money, we will need to list the items to buy, and consider which items are expensive or cheap, what is the quality of it to choose to buy or not, in order to still buy necessary items without exceeding the amount of money that can be spent.</p>



<p>Or, when you have an exam next week, instead of burying yourself in studying everything from now on without any order, any topic, before studying, you will arrange the knowledge by topic, learn about the test layout to know where to focus on and allocate time for the exam properly.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><strong><strong>The essence of logical thinking is to interpret a result or solve a problem in a logical way, thereby standardizing that process into problems and formulas of your own.</strong></strong></p>
</blockquote>



<p>Similar to when you study math, you learn about distance formulas, velocity calculations, or calculus formulas, integrals. You study theorems, etc.</p>



<p>For example: for a, b, c as the 3 sides of a triangle, if the sum of the squares of any 2 sides equals the square of the remaining side, then the triangle is a right-angled triangle. Or when you encounter problems related to integration, just apply the correct mindset and integration formulas, and you&#8217;ll get the result.</p>



<p>When encountering a problem, you just need to identify its type and then apply the correct formula and approach for that type of problem to obtain the correct result. The more you practice, the higher your experience and skills will be, and you will find it easier to solve.</p>



<p>The only difference is that the formulas you learn have been proven by others and are specifically clear by type. In life, the problems you encounter are not only confined to a specific topic, and unexpected factors may arise, moreover, your formulas have not been proven by anyone yet and you have to prove it yourself, at least for yourself.</p>



<p>So you need to always use logical thinking to detect the flaws in your formula, then make corrections, arguments, proceed logically, prove based on facts so that you can find the most comprehensive formula that is right for you.</p>



<p>From there, you will find your own recipes for success.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-methods-for-training-logical-thinking-ability">3. Methods for training logical thinking ability.</h2>



<p>Logical thinking is not an innate talent, but a skill that can be trained and developed. Like any other part of the body, the brain also needs to be trained daily to become more independent, agile, and logical.</p>



<p>Therefore, to improve our logical thinking abilities, we can apply the following methods to train logical thinking.</p>



<div id="always-start-with-the-questions-why-and-how" class="index-title"></div><h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="always-start-with-the-questions-why-and-how">Always start with the questions &#8220;Why?&#8221; and &#8220;How?&#8221;.</h3>



<p>These questions are like signs. When you ask yourself these, it means your brain understands that it needs to think and interpret that process logically in order to determine the cause and the process of problem formation clearly.</p>



<p><strong>&#8211; Why:</strong> This question will help you understand the cause or reason behind an issue or decision. In this way, you can analyze the logical basis and determine the relationship between different factors.</p>



<p><strong>&#8211; How:</strong> This question will help you focus on the process or method to carry out a task or achieve a goal. It requires you to think about the specific steps, procedure, or method to solve a problem.</p>



<p>The more you want to know clearly, in detail why and how your brain needs to think logically more, the more you know what you have to do, the more you understand the process of creating that problem.</p>



<p>From there, you will find the <strong>formula</strong> and can customize it to achieve the results you desire.</p>



<div id="improve-your-own-knowledge" class="index-title"></div><h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="improve-your-own-knowledge">Improve your own knowledge.</h3>



<p><code>You have more knowledge, your understanding of the issues you need to solve increases. The more information you have, the more tightly linked and logical you can create, thereby generating more new and effective methods.</code></p>



<p>In addition, improving your knowledge also helps broaden your mind, stimulates brain activity, leads to new ways of thinking, new perspectives, and enhances your creativity.</p>



<p>You can broaden your knowledge by reading books, stories, watching movies, playing games, and learning new skills. There are plenty of book genres, stories, movies, games, or new skills for you to choose from, so just pick the genre you like.</p>



<p>No matter what the genre, what matters is that you always remember to ask the question <strong>&#8220;Why?&#8221;</strong> and <strong>&#8220;How?&#8221;</strong> whenever you have a question during that process, try to think and answer it. That process will make your brain actively work, which means you constantly have to think logically.</p>



<p>From then on, your logical thinking abilities will continuously improve, and you will also gain more valuable information.</p>



<p>If you don&#8217;t know what to read or learn, don&#8217;t worry, consider it a problem and ask &#8220;Why?&#8221; and &#8220;How?&#8221; Then you will find a way to solve the problem, and that is also the process that helps you develop logical thinking.</p>



<p>The more detailed information you have about the issue, the deeper your understanding of it will be, and the more perspectives and methods you will have to solve the problem. From there, you can come up with a suitable plan and course of action to resolve it.</p>



<p>Similar to what was written in The Art of War.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>To know oneself is true progress.</strong></p>
</blockquote>



<div id="develop-logical-thinking-through-debate-and-exchange" class="index-title"></div><h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="develop-logical-thinking-through-debate-and-exchange">Develop logical thinking through debate and exchange.</h3>



<p>When you participate in discussions and exchanges, people often consider what they say to be right and present evidence, reasoning, analysis, and strong arguments to defend their opinions or refute the opinions of others.</p>



<p>And so are you, there are things that you believe to be right but there will be people who do not believe, reject your opinion. Trying to prove and persuade others of the correctness of what you put forward will greatly enhance your logical thinking ability.</p>



<p>In addition, exposing yourself to various perspectives, thoughts, and different <strong>formulas</strong> will also help you gain more insights, expand your knowledge, and broaden your mind.</p>



<p>At the same time, it also enhances your communication skills and knowledge of how to listen and understand others&#8217; perspectives, helping you to be more flexible and proactive when encountering and dealing with different issues.</p>



<div id="train-logical-thinking-through-real-life-experiences-and-issues" class="index-title"></div><h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="train-logical-thinking-through-real-life-experiences-and-issues">Train logical thinking through real-life experiences and issues.</h3>



<p>The most effective way to train logical thinking is none other than the process of solving problems in your own life and the real experiences you go through. Thinking is not just confined to books, to theories, but is also developed through practical actions.</p>



<p>When you experience things on your own terms, you will develop knowledge and perspectives for yourself. At the same time, it will also help you gain skills and insights that you would never understand just by thinking alone.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-conclusion">4. Conclusion.</h2>



<p>No one knows everything since birth, so they have to seek, strive to learn, explore, develop and enhance their logical thinking skills and other skills, from which they will surpass others by 10 times, 100 times. Only then can they be called a genius.</p>



<p>So keep striving to train, training logical thinking, and one&#8217;s own skills will help you become more agile, confident, and proficient in life, helping you shorten the time to achieve your goals.</p>
<div class="pld-like-dislike-wrap pld-template-2">
    <div class="pld-like-wrap  pld-common-wrap">
    <a href="javascript:void(0)" class="pld-like-trigger pld-like-dislike-trigger  " title="" data-post-id="1663" data-trigger-type="like" data-restriction="cookie" data-already-liked="0">
                        <i class="fas fa-heart"></i>
                </a>
    <span class="pld-like-count-wrap pld-count-wrap">1    </span>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../what-is-logical-thinking-the-role-and-methods-of-training-logical-thinking-ability/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1663</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
