<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Life &#8211; Reach Your Life</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../../index.html</link>
	<description>hiểu rõ chính mình, định hình tương lai, đạt được hạnh phúc</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 18:19:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/01/cropped-image_2024-01-17_173413523-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Life &#8211; Reach Your Life</title>
	<link>./../../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">228209872</site>	<item>
		<title>What is the True Meaning of Wealth?</title>
		<link>./../../../what-is-the-true-meaning-of-wealth/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../what-is-the-true-meaning-of-wealth/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ReachYL]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 19:42:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-growth]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../../index.html?p=1443</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The reason why most people never achieve "wealth" is because they don't truly understand the meaning of "wealth". So what is the true meaning.....]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/what-true-meaning-wealth-elliot-begoun" target="_blank" rel="noopener"></a>Most people, when they mention <strong>&#8220;wealth</strong>&#8220;, understand that wealth means having a lot of money, valuable assets, etc. And they often have love or hate for wealth.</p>



<p>Some people feel angry towards those who have money, but spend their whole life trying to earn as much money as they do. The reason most people never achieve &#8220;wealth&#8221; is because they do not truly understand <strong>the</strong> <strong>true meaning of wealth.</strong></p>



<p><strong><strong>So what is the true meaning of wealth?</strong></strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-black-color has-text-color has-link-color wp-elements-85cb735216735f84eecce86fecb2838d" style="font-size:28px"><strong>1. &#8220;Wealthy&#8221; is when you no longer need to make an effort to earn money to sustain your daily life.</strong></h2>



<p>When you don&#8217;t need to go to work to make money from a job day in and day out, but still can live comfortably. To put it bluntly, you can go to bed without doing anything and still have money.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="674" src="./../../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/01/image-3.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1355" srcset="./../../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/01/image-3.png 1024w, ./../../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/01/image-3-300x197.png 300w, ./../../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/01/image-3-768x506.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p class="has-contrast-color has-text-color has-background has-link-color wp-elements-e9b5ff519c10bfaaf05cee54b4f296b4" style="background-color:#d0cdcd"><strong><strong>So where does the money come from?</strong></strong></p>



<p>The amount comes from the things that help you make money even when you sleep, meaning from your passive income sources.</p>



<p>Passive income sources can come from:</p>



<ul>
<li> bank interest rates</li>



<li> advertising from videos on youtube, personal websites, …</li>



<li> selling digital products such as: audio, beats, ebooks, websites, &#8230;</li>



<li> investment items such as stock investment, digital currency, …</li>
</ul>



<p>Those are the specific jobs that require direct involvement in order to earn money, such as being a wage laborer, an employee, etc. These are your active sources of income. These jobs require you to exchange your health and time for money. If you no longer do these jobs, then for sure you will have no more money.</p>



<p>But our time and health are limited, you can&#8217;t work forever, so if you want to become &#8220;rich,&#8221; you need to find activities, things that can help you generate passive income.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-center">&#8220;Depending on the amount of money that makes you feel happy with life,<br>create passive income sources for yourself so that they always exceed that amount of expenses.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>



<p><strong>Example:</strong> <br>+ Suppose you only need 15 million VND per month, then you can live comfortably and feel happy with life. Therefore, you need to create a passive income greater than 15 million VND per month, and then you will have found wealth for yourself.</p>



<p>+ If, for example, someone needs to spend 200 million per month to achieve the happiness they desire, then that person will need to generate a passive income greater than 200 million per month in order to become wealthy.</p>



<p>And an undeniable fact is that if you spend more than you earn, the only result you will achieve is debt and borrowing.</p>



<p><strong><strong>=&gt; Being wealthy means that your passive income must exceed the amount you need to spend to help you feel happy with life.</strong></strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-black-color has-text-color has-link-color wp-elements-8625d55e83fd8f51c86c5c43fe989e81"><strong>2. Happiness is Wealth</strong>.</h2>



<p>Ultimately, the desire for wealth is aimed at improving one&#8217;s quality of life, to alleviate worries about paying for electricity, rent, and daily expenses, to have the freedom to buy things one truly enjoys without constantly worrying about the cost, and to be able to provide the best for beloved family and friends.</p>



<p><strong><strong>=&gt; To make your life more meaningful, happier.</strong></strong></p>



<p>You don&#8217;t have to become as wealthy as someone else, you don&#8217;t have to make as much money as they do to become rich. What you need is to know how much is enough to make you feel happy.</p>



<p>The rich and the successful, they all know their goals, they understand themselves, know what they truly like, and how much is enough for them.</p>



<p>Based on my interviews and research on wealthy individuals, there are many affluent people who lead a very simple lifestyle, and this <strong>accounts for over 80%</strong> of such individuals in the wealthy community. For example: Bill Gates, Mark Zuckerberg, Warren Buffett, Amancio Ortega, and so on.</p>



<p>But there are many people with not very high salaries who still want to buy luxury clothing, expensive handbags, spending on impulsive desires, therefore it almost does not bring value to the development but only makes you always in a state of lack of money, out of money.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not saying that they are wealthy, they don&#8217;t use money, but one thing for sure is that they spend a lot, however, <strong>the amount they spend is always less than the amount of their passive income</strong>.</p>



<p>And especially, they do not spend money on things that they see as not helpful in their lives, desires that are impulsive, on the contrary, they will definitely spend generously on what they need, what they really like, what helps them develop themselves and increase their passive income stream.</p>



<p>By understanding their own lives, their personalities, and their tastes, they can minimize spending on unnecessary things and maximize spending on other essential needs to become more developed. That is one of the reasons why the rich get richer.</p>



<p><strong>=&gt; When you understand your own personality, your current life, and the life you desire in the future, that&#8217;s when you will find happiness, and that is also the wealth you desire.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-black-color has-text-color has-link-color wp-elements-c2bbabbd8ee382c26a9c9d4f3821e74d">*** <strong><strong>Conclusion</strong>:</strong></h2>



<p>I think by now, you all understand what I am aiming for. Now, I believe each of you has a definition of &#8220;wealth&#8221; that you want to achieve in the future. It&#8217;s not about seeking the wealth of others, but about seeking your own wealth.</p>
<div class="pld-like-dislike-wrap pld-template-2">
    <div class="pld-like-wrap  pld-common-wrap">
    <a href="javascript:void(0)" class="pld-like-trigger pld-like-dislike-trigger  " title="" data-post-id="1443" data-trigger-type="like" data-restriction="cookie" data-already-liked="0">
                        <i class="fas fa-heart"></i>
                </a>
    <span class="pld-like-count-wrap pld-count-wrap">    </span>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../what-is-the-true-meaning-of-wealth/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1443</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to understand yourself better</title>
		<link>./../../../how-to-understand-yourself-better/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../how-to-understand-yourself-better/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ReachYL]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 19:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-growth]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../../index.html?p=1438</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have had a period of feeling lost in life because I didn&#8217;t know what my purpose was. During that time, I was constantly overthinking, which led to frustration, exhaustion, mental depletion, and a lack of energy to do anything else. Day after day, I find myself immersed in thoughts about myself, not knowing what &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I have had a period of feeling lost in life because I didn&#8217;t know what my purpose was. During that time, I was constantly overthinking, which led to frustration, exhaustion, mental depletion, and a lack of energy to do anything else.</p>



<p>Day after day, I find myself immersed in thoughts about myself, not knowing what I truly like, not knowing what my goals and dreams are, and not knowing how to understand myself better.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">That made me feel lost, tired, exhausted, not wanting to interact, talk to other people. Every day I isolate myself more, I don&#8217;t understand myself, and then I don&#8217;t want to make any effort to do anything else in life, when I&#8217;m so exhausted I just fall asleep.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">My life keeps repeating itself, and gradually I feel like it doesn&#8217;t have any meaning.</p>



<p>Only when there are unforeseen events, things that I did not expect, things that appear new in my life, it turns my previous life upside down, making me feel things that I had never experienced in my previous life.</p>



<p>After going through all that, I realized that my life is meaningful in many ways. I finally understood that the things I have been thinking about all along, the answers I needed have always been right in front of me, I just didn&#8217;t realize it back then.</p>



<p>Now I know how to understand myself better, find goals, and dreams that I want to pursue.</p>



<p>I think many of you, like me, have experienced a period of feeling lost, not knowing &#8220;who I am&#8221;. But eventually, you have found the answers to those questions, understood yourselves better, and found a happy life.</p>



<p>But there are also many people who are currently stuck in that cycle, sinking into their own thoughts without being able to escape, and then their spirits become weakened and no longer want to do anything else. Gradually losing themselves, being wrapped up in others, and enduring that life even though they don&#8217;t feel happy.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why I wrote this blog with the desire to share a journey that helped me understand myself better, which I realized during that difficult time. I hope that what I share here will help you somewhat in understanding yourself better, helping you find value in your own life.</p>



<div class="wp-block-rank-math-toc-block" id="rank-math-toc" id="rank-math-toc"><h2>Mục Lục</h2><nav><ul><li ><a href="#1-add-new-things-to-your-painting">1. Add new things to your &#8220;painting&#8221;</a></li><li ><a href="#2-take-time-to-talk-and-listen-to-yourself">2.  Take time to talk and listen to yourself</a><ul><li ><a href="#2-1-what-will-happen-when-you-no-longer-spend-time-for-yourself">2.1. What will happen when you no longer spend time for yourself? </a></li><li ><a href="#2-2-the-things-you-gain-when-talking-listening-to-yourself">2.2. The things you gain when talking, listening to yourself..</a></li></ul></li><li ><a href="#3-open-up-and-share-your-thoughts-with-someone-you-trust">3. Open up and share your thoughts with someone you trust.</a></li><li ><a href="#4-foster-your-imagination-and-creativity">4. Foster your imagination and creativity.</a></li><li ><a href="#conclusion">*** Conclusion</a></li></ul></nav></div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-black-color has-text-color has-link-color wp-elements-d66e08d31ce597c2c685c67e94345641" id="1-add-new-things-to-your-painting"><strong>1. Add new things to your &#8220;<strong>painting</strong>&#8220;</strong></h2>



<p>Imagine your life as a painting, if the things you are seeking are not present in that painting, you will never find them. Or if those things have not yet taken on a specific form and are only at the sketching stage, you will not recognize them either.</p>



<p>That is why, seek additional ideas and sources of inspiration from other paintings, from outside of your painting, to envision many possibilities for your artwork. Add different colors to &#8220;your painting,&#8221; these colors could be:</p>



<p>+ New friends.<br>+ New knowledge.<br>+ New activities.<br>+ Things that you&#8217;ve never tried before.</p>



<p>( And of course, without violating the law ;3 )</p>



<p>Don&#8217;t worry about whether you like it or not, because what you need to do is <strong>stop thinking</strong> and <strong>just give it a try</strong>. All of those things will make your &#8220;picture&#8221; messy and not as it used to be.</p>



<p>Those things will help you have new thoughts, new perspectives, and new feelings about things that you would never see if you always stayed in your old life.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-center has-black-color has-text-color has-link-color wp-elements-bae85ab95cc35b3bbd11eeb65c6987aa"><strong>&#8220;<strong>A same formula will never yield different results.</strong>&#8220;</strong>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">If you continue to maintain a life like that,<br>then what you receive will not change.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>So do not let laziness, difficulties, hesitation, and fear prevent you from stepping out of your current life, to seek new things in life, to understand yourself better, to find your own worth, to find your own happiness.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-black-color has-text-color has-link-color wp-elements-8b090291d1269b86b9d85d7bda2fb4f8" id="2-take-time-to-talk-and-listen-to-yourself"><strong>2. <strong>&nbsp;Take time to talk and listen to yourself</strong></strong></h2>



<div id="2-1-what-will-happen-when-you-no-longer-spend-time-for-yourself" class="index-title"></div><h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-1-what-will-happen-when-you-no-longer-spend-time-for-yourself"><strong>2.1. <strong>What will happen when you no longer spend time for yourself?</strong> </strong></h3>



<p>After experiencing many things you have never felt before. The joys you have never had, the pains you have never suffered, meeting people with a very beautiful &#8220;painting&#8221; and also people who cannot even have a complete piece of paper for their &#8220;painting&#8221;. Then you realize that your previous life was so boring.</p>



<p>And at the same time, you will also realize that there are too many things in this life that you want, you will be swept away by those fleeting desires, you will be wrapped up in the beauty of other &#8220;paintings,&#8221; and then you will have no time for your own painting, and once again you will be lost in a pile of chaotic things.</p>



<p>Gradually, you will forget the person inside yourself, forgetting the things that make you truly happy in life, to pursue fleeting emotions and pleasures.</p>



<p>And then at some point in the future, you will realize that you have wasted time, health, and money on things that are not worth the value you have put into them, and then you will feel very regretful about it.</p>



<div id="2-2-the-things-you-gain-when-talking-listening-to-yourself" class="index-title"></div><h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-2-the-things-you-gain-when-talking-listening-to-yourself"><strong>2.2. <strong>The things you gain when talking, listening to yourself.</strong>.</strong></h3>



<p>That&#8217;s why, whenever you experience something, always take a moment to dedicate some time for yourself during the day, in a quiet environment, where there is only you and yourself, to talk, to tell yourself what you have been through.</p>



<p>At this time, just say what you think, speak of what you experience, both the happy and the sad, express your doubts, what makes you upset, don&#8217;t hide anything because you are talking to yourself. Speak out loud, or you can write it down on paper and read it.</p>



<p>What you recount is also how your brain is shaping, rearranging what you are thinking, experiencing, and from that, you will gain insights, find answers to things that puzzle you.</p>



<p>In addition, you should relax your body and mind, contemplate, think about the things you&#8217;ve been through, and then you will feel the most genuine emotions from within yourself. That&#8217;s how you can talk and listen to yourself.</p>



<p>Listening to yourself will help you understand what you like, what you hate, what is best for you, what is harmful to you, your strengths, your weaknesses, your dreams, your goals, what truly brings you happiness. From there, you will have your own perspective and will not be pushed around by life indefinitely.</p>



<p>In other words, it will help you understand yourself better.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-open-up-and-share-your-thoughts-with-someone-you-trust"><strong>3. Open up and share your thoughts with someone you trust.</strong></h2>



<p>This is quite similar to talking to yourself, with the only difference being that instead of speaking to yourself, you are conversing with someone else. This someone else could be your friends, family, your significant other, someone who makes you feel comfortable and close when talking, someone you trust.</p>



<p>When talking to yourself, you can take the time to self-analyze, contemplate life, and process emotions in private. But when speaking to others, you can share your emotions, thoughts, life, and experiences with the person in front of you.</p>



<p>In addition, the person you share with will also listen, share their own stories, thoughts, perspectives, knowledge, and provide sincere advice for you.</p>



<p>From there, you will have new perspectives, you will learn about the hidden corners of yourself that you have never realized before, those things will help you a lot in understanding yourself better.</p>



<p>Not only that, sharing and confiding with each other will also help both of them understand each other better, making their relationship closer and more intimate.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-foster-your-imagination-and-creativity"><strong>4. <strong>Foster your imagination and creativity</strong>.</strong></h2>



<p>Cultivating your imagination and creativity is crucial because as you understand yourself better and learn more about different aspects of yourself, your imagination and creativity are what will help you develop and explore all the great potential within you.</p>



<p>It is what makes you enjoy what you are doing even more, making your goals clearer and more meaningful.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s something that helps you to find new methods, new ways of thinking, and new changes that quickly help you achieve your goals.</p>



<p>And at the same time, this will also create more new and interesting things for you in your life. It allows you to imagine the new things that you can add to your own &#8220;picture&#8221;.</p>



<p>When you have ideas, just start working on them. Those actions will help you gain new experiences, new perspectives, and that is exactly the first thing I told you above<br>&#8220;<strong>1. Add new things to your &#8220;painting</strong>&#8220;.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-black-color has-text-color has-link-color wp-elements-6a0bed85b9ca92539cc064d67a549931" id="conclusion"><strong>*** <strong>Conclusion</strong></strong></h2>



<p>Understanding oneself is a process similar to learning, and this process will never end. It will continue to repeat, because every time we learn new things, as time passes and our age changes, as society changes and affects our lives, our thoughts and desires also change accordingly.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why we need to constantly repeat that process to understand ourselves better, then we will never lose ourselves.</p>
<div class="pld-like-dislike-wrap pld-template-2">
    <div class="pld-like-wrap  pld-common-wrap">
    <a href="javascript:void(0)" class="pld-like-trigger pld-like-dislike-trigger  " title="" data-post-id="1438" data-trigger-type="like" data-restriction="cookie" data-already-liked="0">
                        <i class="fas fa-heart"></i>
                </a>
    <span class="pld-like-count-wrap pld-count-wrap">    </span>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../how-to-understand-yourself-better/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1438</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
