<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Vũ Minh Nguyệt &#8211; Reach Your Life</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../../index.html</link>
	<description>hiểu rõ chính mình, định hình tương lai, đạt được hạnh phúc</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:32:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/01/cropped-image_2024-01-17_173413523-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Vũ Minh Nguyệt &#8211; Reach Your Life</title>
	<link>./../../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">228209872</site>	<item>
		<title>4 Values that sales departments bring to you</title>
		<link>./../../../4-value-that-sales-departments-bring-to-you/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../4-value-that-sales-departments-bring-to-you/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vũ Minh Nguyệt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 15:05:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../../index.html?p=1403</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After a period of internship in the Sales of business, I have gained many values that the business department brings.
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>With a background in economics, doing an internship early on has always been a &#8220;thorny issue&#8221; for me when I first stepped into the university environment. After a first semester of being aimless and directionless, I was determined to do an internship in the second semester. Anything office-related would do as I was so &#8220;thirsty&#8221; for experience. I chose to intern in the sales departments  because as an economics student, I firmly believe that it would be difficult for me to produce any goods. Skills in marketing and product circulation would be most suitable and help me develop in the long term.</p>



<p>So what values that sales departments have I gained during my time with the company and the job?</p>



<div class="wp-block-rank-math-toc-block" id="rank-math-toc" id="rank-math-toc"><h2>Mục Lục</h2><nav><ul><li ><a href="#1-sales-experience">1. Sales experience</a><ul><li ><a href="#1-1-professional-skills">1.1. Professional Skills:</a></li><li ><a href="#1-2-soft-skills">1.2. Soft skills:</a></li></ul></li><li ><a href="#2-networking">2. Networking</a></li><li ><a href="#3-salary">3. Salary</a></li><li ><a href="#4-understanding-the-industry-better-instead-of-being-bogged-down-by-prejudices-from-the-past">4. Understanding the industry better instead of being bogged down by prejudices from the past</a></li><li ><a href="#conclusion">*** Conclusion </a></li></ul></nav></div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-sales-experience"><strong>1. Sales experience</strong></h2>



<p>Experience is surely the top priority for every student, and I am no exception. I was so eager for experience that I went to many places to apply for unpaid internships in exchange for the guidance from more experienced people. Naturally, I was rejected many times, but fortunately, I ended up where I am working now.</p>



<p>Professional skills and soft skills are two core values that I receive:</p>



<div id="1-1-professional-skills" class="index-title"></div><h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-1-professional-skills">1.1. <strong><strong>Professional Skills:</strong></strong></h3>



<p>The sales position teaches me practical knowledge and a deeper understanding than what is taught in the &#8220;Business Management&#8221; and &#8220;Basic Marketing&#8221; books. It&#8217;s completely different from just reading and feeling vague and distant when not working.</p>



<p>Working experience also helps me understand more about the enterprise, how the business operates, and gain a basic understanding of the work of different departments within the company.</p>



<p>I have been studying human analysis tools such as numerology, DISC, … to gain a deeper understanding and improve myself, as well as to advise and support customers in guiding and overcoming difficulties in learning, and life issues.</p>



<p>I have the opportunity to learn about and get involved in Marketing, a field that I have always liked and nurtured for a long time.</p>



<div id="1-2-soft-skills" class="index-title"></div><h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-2-soft-skills">1.2. <strong><strong>Soft skills:</strong></strong></h3>



<p><strong>+ Communication</strong>: I have improved my communication skills through conversations with clients, managers, and colleagues. My job has pushed me to step out of my comfort zone, actively connect and engage. Communication is an art, skillful communication will support me and my colleagues in work and life, as my boss once taught me &#8220;the mouth helps the hands and feet&#8221;, truly impressive and revealing. Not only in work negotiations, but also in personal relationships such as family, friends, and partners, I have learned to regulate emotions, communicate skillfully to discuss issues and find solutions as well as general communication, instead of having to endure or create conversations that end in arguments and toxicity.</p>



<p><strong>+ Self-management: </strong>Unlike the dull energy lying in dorm room 1, scrolling through the phone all day, when I go to work, interact with the new environment, new friends, and new colleagues, I feel the energy of everyone, also &#8220;absorb&#8221; excitement and consciously push myself to study well, manage time.</p>



<p><strong>+ Time management:</strong>&nbsp;It&#8217;s still a story from semester 1, studying only 4 subjects but always feeling lacking and suffocated, all because of too much free time and laziness, &#8220;spending time on useless things and lacking time for necessary things.&#8221; Until starting to work, meeting those senior colleagues, those friends who also balanced study and work very well, received scholarships regularly every semester, won in various competitions, only then did I feel the pressure to arrange and be aware of studying to not fall behind. Now, I not only make a to-do list for each day, but also need to plan for the whole month, also thankful for the nature of the job that helped me learn how to improve myself.</p>



<p><strong>+</strong> <strong>Gratitude:</strong>&nbsp;Before going to work, I was involved in a volunteer club and initially felt overwhelmed by the strict rules. However, when I started working, learning about gratitude culture and expressing thanks, I became much more proactive, showing more gratitude and admiration for those who have led and taught me. I learned the mindset of &#8220;an empty cup,&#8221; accepting the teachings of others rather than acting like &#8220;I already know half of it,&#8221; as in the past.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-networking"><strong>2. Networking</strong></h2>



<p>I am connected and working with experienced mentors, both in work and life, people that I would never have the chance to contact if I didn&#8217;t go to work.</p>



<p>I have added truly quality and sustainable relationships when accompanying each other in work and development, those who are willing to listen and help when I need, those intimate &#8220;boards of directors&#8221; like family.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-salary"><strong>3. Salary</strong></h2>



<p>I receive a salary that matches my dedication, and going to work early makes me value money early, value my parents&#8217; labor, and spend more reasonably.</p>



<div class="wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container is-layout-constrained wp-block-group-is-layout-constrained">
<div class="wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container is-layout-constrained wp-block-group-is-layout-constrained">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-understanding-the-industry-better-instead-of-being-bogged-down-by-prejudices-from-the-past"><strong>4. Understanding the industry better instead of being bogged down by prejudices from the past</strong></h2>



<p>Employees of the sales department, the name of this position is Sale. Most people have stereotypes about sales, and I was like that too, but I decided to try it out to see what really suits me, and I have received a lot of values like the above &#8211; something that if I just stick with a biased mindset, I will never receive.</p>



<p>Sales is an essential part of business, and being a best seller is highly valuable in the eyes of employers. From my experience, there is no bad industry; every profession is worthwhile and contributes to social development. The difference lies in each person&#8217;s way of working. Being a caring salesperson, accompanying and supporting customers throughout the use of the service or product, to help them achieve the best results, is a very humane job. My quality networking includes not only colleagues and bosses, but also the customers I have advised and supported.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="conclusion">*** <strong>Conclusion</strong>&nbsp;</h2>



<p>After nearly 1 year of perseverance, I went from being an Intern to a Supervisor. I am grateful to the colleague who guided me to this job, thankful for the mentors who provided guidance and instruction, appreciative of the teammates who worked alongside me to achieve our goals, and thankful to myself for persevering without giving up.</p>



<p>If you are also an economist, then the position in the business department is worth applying for and experiencing as well as developing yourself.</p>
</div></div>
</div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../4-value-that-sales-departments-bring-to-you/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1403</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
